{
  "baseline-test-i-cybersecurity":[{"question":"Which of the following statements about cybersecurity is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping physical information secure. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping digital information secure. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping physical and digital information secure. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a possible consequence of a cybersecurity threat? ","answers":[{"text":"We can no longer pay bills. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Employees can no longer contact clients. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Clients, partners, and employees lose trust in the organization. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why do businesses work hard on their cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"Because they often cooperate with other companies. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because a cybersecurity threat can have huge financial consequences. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To conform with the privacy regulations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is cybersecurity important? ","answers":[{"text":"Because incidents can endanger the health and safety of people. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because some incidents cannot be solved. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because this is how you prevent unauthorized access to the office. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does malware threaten cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"By damaging or erasing information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By installing malicious hardware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By automatically opening attachments in phishing emails. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You use the internet in public. When is this a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"When you set up a device as a hotspot. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use mobile internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Is it safe to store information in a public cloud? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, public cloud services are well protected and therefore secure. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because some public cloud services are allowed to access your files. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, because everyone has access to the information in a public cloud. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do IoT devices pose a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"Because they are easy to hack. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because they break easily. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because they tend to lose their connection to the internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do phishers operate? ","answers":[{"text":"They listen in when you are having a confidential discussion in public. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They send emails in which they ask for personal or business information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They search wastepaper bins to find personal or business information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the IoT pose a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"When different devices do not communicate with each other properly, a data leak occurs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you forget your password, it is difficult to access personal information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When default passwords are not changed, hackers can get easy access to sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When do cybercriminals commit spoofing? ","answers":[{"text":"When they replicate a website. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they spread malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When they break into a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The sender is not familiar. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The sender cannot be found on the internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The sender's name does not match the email address. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which characteristics of an email suggest the possibility of a phishing attempt? ","answers":[{"text":"It arrives at night. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It starts with a general greeting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It doesn't have a subject. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The images are not downloaded automatically. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It has an attachment. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It requests personal information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which sentence is a sign of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"'Go to our website to see all offers.' ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"'Click on the link, register and win a free iPad.' ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"'Dear Peter, we have a wonderful offer for you!' ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect your IoT devices? ","answers":[{"text":"By turning off the internet connection whenever it is not needed. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By only connecting the devices with your own Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By only connecting the devices with mobile internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you reduce the risk of infection with malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By regularly making backups of your programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By keeping programs up to date. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By keeping new programs in the downloads folder. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why should you make regular backups? ","answers":[{"text":"To secure information in the event of a crash or a malware infection. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To keep information available to all your colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To keep information available when you are offline. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When does an antivirus program have to be enabled? ","answers":[{"text":"Only when you suspect a threat. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"At least once a day. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Always. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is your use of the IoT secure? ","answers":[{"text":"When you use the same strong password for each device. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use a different strong password for each device. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you use the default password for each device, because it is a strong password. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You have a new IoT device. In what way do you change the login information? ","answers":[{"text":"You change the default username to your email address. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You use the password that is given in the user manual. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You change the default password to a new strong password. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You receive a request via email to send personal information. What is the best thing to do? ","answers":[{"text":"Check whether the sender is allowed to receive the information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Do not provide the information and delete the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Send the requested information, but also ask for an explanation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You receive a suspicious email. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Delete the email and notify your immediate colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Notify the responsible person or department. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Block the sender and delete the email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good way to remember your passwords? ","answers":[{"text":"Write them down in a password logbook. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Keep them in a secured Excel file. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use a password manager. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is two-factor authentication? ","answers":[{"text":"The protection of your login information with two different strong passwords. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The protection of your login information with a strong password and a one-time code, a fingerprint, a hard token, etc. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The protection of your login information with a password in which you have used at least two different types of characters. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the most secure way to use the internet in public? ","answers":[{"text":"Using a secure Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using mobile internet. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why should you use a VPN when using public internet? ","answers":[{"text":"A VPN stops phishing emails. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A VPN blocks infected ads. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A VPN encrypts all information that you send. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why should you remove cookies regularly? ","answers":[{"text":"Cookies follow you around the internet. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Cookies spread malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cookies slow down your internet speed. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the privacy settings of social media accounts is true? ","answers":[{"text":"They can barely be changed, which makes your information visible to everyone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They are often automatically set to “public”, which makes your information visible to everyone. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They are often automatically set to “private”, which makes your information invisible to strangers. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good practice when using social media? ","answers":[{"text":"Giving serious thought to posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Checking your privacy settings before posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Not posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is a good way to protect your online privacy? ","answers":[{"text":"Using an ad blocker in your browser. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Not using social media at work. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using an antivirus program. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good step toward making mobile devices criminal-proof? ","answers":[{"text":"Install the latest software version. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Disable the location features of your device. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Set up a strong password or biometric recognition. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "baseline-test-i-gdpr":[{"question":"How should you provide data subjects with information about the processing of their personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"In a way that is easy for the processing organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a way that is understandable and easily accessible for the data subjects. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In a way that describes the processing in detail. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast do organizations need to respond when data subjects ask for information? ","answers":[{"text":"As soon as possible, but within one month at the latest. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Within one month. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within one week. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When do data subjects have the right to receive information? ","answers":[{"text":"Whenever you process their personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only when you adjust something in the processing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when you process special personal data about them. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"To what are data subjects entitled? ","answers":[{"text":"To endorse the way organizations protect their data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To decide where organizations store their data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To see what data organizations have regarding them. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should organizations show to data subjects? ","answers":[{"text":"How their system for data processing works. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"What they do with the data of the data subjects. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Whether they process the same data of other data subjects. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast do organizations need to modify or make an addition to personal data in the event of incorrect or incomplete processing? ","answers":[{"text":"Within one month. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within five business days. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"May data subjects ask the processing organizations to delete their data? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, that is always allowed. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless other interests prevail. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, that is not allowed. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Do data subjects have the right to limit the processing of their data? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, but only in certain situations. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, processing cannot be limited. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, only the processing organization may determine whether they want to limit the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When data subjects ask for their personal data, how should organizations provide it to them? ","answers":[{"text":"On paper. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In any way the organization chooses. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a usual way. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When data subjects receive their personal data from an organization, may they pass them on to another organization? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only in certain situations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"To what may data subjects object? ","answers":[{"text":"To the measures that organizations take to protect their personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To the processing of their personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To the outsourcing of the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When data subjects have objected, is an organization obliged to stop the processing? ","answers":[{"text":"No, the organization may decide this themselves. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless the processing goal has not yet been achieved. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless the organization has a compelling, justified reason. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When are data subjects entitled to a personal assessment of their situation in the case of the automated processing of personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When they ask for it. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When a decision has major consequences for them. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When the automated processing uses wrong data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Is the controller obliged to process the personal data himself? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because it is his responsibility. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, he may outsource it to the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, he may outsource it to a processor. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Does the controller have to register all processing activities in writing? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, this is his responsibility. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Yes, but only when he does not outsource the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, the supervisory authority has this register. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the controller need to report a data breach to the supervisory authority when data subjects are at risk? ","answers":[{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 24 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 36 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 72 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What data breaches does the controller need to register? ","answers":[{"text":"All data breaches. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only data breaches that put data subjects at risk. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only data breaches that involve the leakage of special personal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the controller need to inform the data subjects of a data breach if they are at high risk? ","answers":[{"text":"Within 72 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within 24 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is the controller liable for paying damages? ","answers":[{"text":"Always. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only when he does not outsource the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he has not fulfilled his obligations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In what situation do organizations have to designate a data protection officer (DPO)? ","answers":[{"text":"When they process financial data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When they process a lot of special personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they make mistakes during processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the controller ensure that the processing complies with the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"By outsourcing the processing to a certified processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By taking appropriate technical and organizational measures. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By asking for permission from the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may a processor process personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When he guarantees to comply with all the requirements of the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a controller gives his approval. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When he is enlisted as a processor at the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do the controller and the processor need to record their arrangements? ","answers":[{"text":"In a written agreement. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In an oral or a written agreement. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In an agreement with the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What must the processor do when he processes personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Keep a written backup of processes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Keep a written record of the processing activities. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Have the controller approve the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the processor need to report a data breach to the controller when he discovers this? ","answers":[{"text":"Within 72 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within 24 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is the processor liable for damages? ","answers":[{"text":"Only when the controller is not liable. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he caused the damage. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he has not fulfilled his obligations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the best way to store personal data safely? ","answers":[{"text":"Digitally. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Encrypted. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Secured with a password. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may people have access to personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When they work for the controller or the processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When it is necessary for the work or the processing. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they guarantee to handle the data safely. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do you need to have a procedure to test, review, and evaluate measures? ","answers":[{"text":"To determine whether you are still effectively protecting personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To let the processing method be endorsed by the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As this is not effectively possible without a procedure. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good way to protect personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Let the data be processed by the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Store the data digitally. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pseudonymize the data. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who or what suffers major consequences when personal data is lost or stolen? ","answers":[{"text":"The processing organization and the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The supervisory authority and the data subjects. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The data subjects and the processing organization. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What sanction can be imposed on organizations for violating the privacy law? ","answers":[{"text":"For future processing, they need to ask permission from the European Commission beforehand. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They need to pay a large fine. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They need to collect the personal data again if they want to use them after the violation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is the good protection of personal data important when processed in countries outside the EU? ","answers":[{"text":"Because you are no longer the owner of the personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because you can easily misinterpret personal data in other languages. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because those countries do not always offer an adequate level of protection. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the largest fine for organizations that violate the law? ","answers":[{"text":"�20 million or 4% of the total worldwide annual turnover. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"�10 million or 4% of the total worldwide annual turnover. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"�10 million or 2% of the total worldwide annual turnover. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about sending personal data to countries outside of the EU is true? ","answers":[{"text":"This is prohibited in accordance with the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"For this, the rules of those countries apply. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"For this, you need to comply with certain conditions. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Only data about someone in combination with a name. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only data that is unique to one particular person. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"All data that directly or indirectly can be linked to someone. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is “special personal data” according to the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"Sensitive data about someone. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Data that can be directly linked to someone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Someone's secrets. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In which situations may you process someone's special personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Only in special situations, for example, with that person's permission. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In the same situations where you may process other personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only if that person is an employee of your organization. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What are examples of special personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Religion and financial data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Biometric data and political preferences. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Health and membership of an association. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the processing of personal data entail? ","answers":[{"text":"Using personal data. On days you do not use them, you do not process them either. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Everything you do with personal data. It does not matter what this is. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Everything from the moment of collecting until the moment of destroying. The destroying itself is not part of the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does privacy ensure? ","answers":[{"text":"It ensures that our data are not the same as the data of others. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It protects us and our information from others. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It keeps our information secret from others. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why was the GDPR implemented? ","answers":[{"text":"To ensure the protection of privacy is the same throughout the EU. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To have the same organization protect privacy throughout the EU. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To ensure that the same measures are applied throughout the EU to protect the privacy of data subjects. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Can different countries in the EU have different rules for the protection of personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"No, the rules in every country are the same. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, countries are free to decide which rules of the GDPR they use. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, countries can make additions or exceptions to certain rules of the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who monitors the proper application of the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"Supervisory authorities. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The local government. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The European Commission. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may you process personal data in accordance with the principle of lawfulness? ","answers":[{"text":"When the data subjects give their permission or when this is necessary for a reason that is stated in the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When this is necessary for a reason that is stated in the GDPR or when you protect the data sufficiently. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you protect the data sufficiently or when the data subjects give their permission. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the principle of purpose limitation work? ","answers":[{"text":"You may only process personal data if you have a clear and valid goal. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you have collected personal data, you must connect them to a clear and valid goal. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may only process personal data if the goal of the organization is the processing of personal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the principle of minimized data processing mean? ","answers":[{"text":"You need to comply with special rules when you process a small amount of personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When organizations process more personal data than is usual in their sector, they need additional permission. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may not process more personal data than is necessary to achieve the processing goals. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What do you need to do to comply with the principle of accuracy? ","answers":[{"text":"Only process personal data if this is allowed in accordance with the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Take all reasonable measures to ensure that the data you process is correct. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only process personal data once you are sure it is correct. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the principle of storage constraints entail? ","answers":[{"text":"That personal data can only be traced back to a specific person as long as this is needed to achieve the processing goals. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That you may only store a certain amount of personal data. The amount depends on the size of the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you may store personal data for a year at the most. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you need to do with personal data in accordance with the principle of integrity and confidentiality? ","answers":[{"text":"You need to protect data with the measures that are stated in the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need approval from the supervisory authority before you may process the data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need to protect data with appropriate technical and organizational measures. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "baseline-test-i-malware":[{"question":"How does malware greatly affect people or organizations? ","answers":[{"text":"By sending threatening emails or stealing money or personal information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By stealing money or personal information, or preventing you from accessing your device. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By preventing you from accessing your device or sending threatening emails. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do organizations increasingly suffer from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because organizations are more and more dependent on ICT. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because malware is becoming increasingly malicious. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because organizations have more trouble detecting malware. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How far does malware spread if an organization is infected with it? ","answers":[{"text":"It spreads only through the department to which the infected computer belongs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It spreads through the entire company network, but not to other organizations. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It spreads through the entire company network or to other organizations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is a slow computer a sign of malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because the computer can do little or nothing else if it is running malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because the computer is partially broken and therefore does not work fast anymore. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because one purpose of malware is to affect the working memory of the computer. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a sign that you are suffering from a malware infection? ","answers":[{"text":"Websites that show ads. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pop-ups that open spontaneously. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You receive emails with an untrustworthy attachment. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By processes that are running while the computer is turned off. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By unknown security software that shows pop-ups. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By software that you did not install yourself. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What often happens to people who suffer from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Emails are sent in their name. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They receive emails from unknown senders. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They can no longer send attachments via email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you tell that you are suffering from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Your antivirus program or other programs no longer work. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Your antivirus program has suddenly disappeared from your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Programs mimic each other's operations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How come you sometimes do not notice malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because malware is sometimes disabled. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because the signs are not always visible right away. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because you must go on the internet before malware is activated. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do to find out if you have malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Restart your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Look for unknown files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Carry out a malware scan. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Do the organization's security systems protect against malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, they are set up especially for that purpose. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, but that does not guarantee anything. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, malware can easily circumvent security systems. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is your role in preventing malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Remaining alert. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Having my computer checked periodically for signs of malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Changing antivirus programs every year. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect your computer against malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By making sure you have secure hardware and software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making sure you have hardware that is not vulnerable to malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making sure you have software that protects against malware. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you regularly do with your programs to prevent getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Reinstall them. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Make backups. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Run updates. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When do you have the greatest chance of getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"When you are logged in as an administrator. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you work on the same computer a lot. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you have recently installed updates. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What risk do free antivirus programs pose? ","answers":[{"text":"They are bad at detecting malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They sometimes contain malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"There are no updates for them. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you get malware via an email from an unknown or unexpected sender? ","answers":[{"text":"By opening the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By opening the attachment. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By answering the email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which ads have the highest chance of containing malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Ads that seem too good to be true. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Ads that have images. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ads that are only valid for a limited time. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Malware infections can be prevented by not using untrustworthy websites. What is an example of an untrustworthy website? ","answers":[{"text":"A website that you have not visited before. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A website that does not end in .net or .org. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A website offering free downloads. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What type of file should you not download if you want to prevent malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Files from people outside the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Free and/or illegal files. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Files that are larger than 2 GB. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What helps to prevent malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Keeping a backup of your files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Reporting suspicious situations and incidents. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Periodically emptying your email inbox. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you help others to prevent their systems from becoming infected with malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By reporting malware to a fraud helpdesk in your country. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By forwarding suspicious emails to colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You cannot help other people; everyone must pay attention themselves. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you remove malware from your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By searching for the malware file and moving it to the trash can on your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By deleting all downloads and updating your programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By completely erasing your hard disk and reinstalling the system and programs. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Can malware be combatted with system restoration? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"This depends on the situation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Malicious hardware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Malicious software. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Hardware containing a virus. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can malware do? ","answers":[{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems or interrupt this access. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems, interrupt this access, or collect sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about malware is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Malware exists in different forms, including hybrid forms. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Malware exists in different forms. There are no hybrid forms. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Malware only has one form. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Can malware end up on your computer via the internet? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, this often happens. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, malware can only end up on your computer via an infected USB stick. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, malware can only end up on your computer if other people infect it. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What type of software increases the chance of getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Software that was not installed by an ICT professional. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Software that is not up to date. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Software that is freely available on the internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does malware end up on your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By updating free software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using free software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By installing free software that is already infected. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How does malware end up on your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By visiting websites that provide free music or movies and by using an unknown USB stick. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By uploading photos to the cloud or by sending emails. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By connecting your phone to the computer to charge it or by clicking on ads. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "baseline-test-i-phishing":[{"question":"What is phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Looking up personal information on the internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Spreading malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A type of scam. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What information do phishers collect? ","answers":[{"text":"Personal data and access data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Access data only. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Personal data only. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do phishers gather information? ","answers":[{"text":"They search for information about you on social media. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They pretend to be someone else to get information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They break into the corporate network to steal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does a phisher ensure that you carry out certain actions? ","answers":[{"text":"A phisher introduces himself and immediately asks you nicely to provide information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A phisher pretends to be someone else and gets you to perform certain actions. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A phisher gives you a gift, hoping that you will perform a certain action in return. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is it important to prevent phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Because phishing can now also damage the hardware of your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing can have a financial impact on an individual employee. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing occurs more often. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is phishing a threat to organizations? ","answers":[{"text":"Because phishing can cause stress to employees. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing can infect your computer with malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because you no longer have access to the intranet due to phishing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a consequence of phishing that you want to prevent? ","answers":[{"text":"That the phishing email overloads your inbox. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That phishers post sensitive information on social media. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That your organization loses information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What consequence of phishing do you want to prevent? ","answers":[{"text":"That customers lose their confidence in your organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That your organization has to update all its programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That your organization must employ new employees to adequately protect the information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you prevent by being alert to phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Physical threats. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Overloading the server(s). ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Reputational damage. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"At whom are basic phishing emails aimed? ","answers":[{"text":"A specific target group. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A wide audience. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Higher management. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is there a case of spear phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When a phishing email is sent to a small group of people. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a phishing email has an anonymous greeting. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When a large group of people are contacted by phone to obtain certain information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is CEO fraud? ","answers":[{"text":"Finding sensitive information about the management or the board. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Sending emails that seem to come from the management or the board. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Sending emails that seem to come from the finance department. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is spoofing? ","answers":[{"text":"Faking real websites or the emails of a reliable organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Sending mass emails to large organizations. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Hacking reliable organizations via their website. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is vishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When someone asks you by phone to share personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a website asks you to click on a link. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When someone asks you to share personal information via social media. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is smishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When you receive an SMS with a strange photo. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you click on a fake URL on your phone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you receive an SMS with a fake URL. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What kind of phishing mail is an example of whaling? ","answers":[{"text":"A personalized phishing mail that was sent to an employee of the financial department. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A phishing mail that was sent to a large group of board members or directors. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A personalized phishing mail that was sent to a member of the board or director. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"By an anonymous greeting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By language use without spelling mistakes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By a logo of a well-known organization. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can be a characteristic of a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The mail contains an attachment. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The mail contains bad spelling and grammar. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The mail does not have a logo in it. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is an email with a link phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When the link is written out in full. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When the link occurs several times in the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When the URL does not match the link in the text. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You recognize phishing by a misleading domain name. Where in the URL is the domain name? ","answers":[{"text":"After the www. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"After the extension (for example .com). ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Before the first single slash. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the use of HTTP and HTTPS is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Phishing links use HTTP more often than HTTPS. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Phishing links use HTTPS more often than HTTP. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"HTTPS means that the link is not phishing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of pop-ups are a sign of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Pop-ups with images. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pop-ups that ask for login details. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Pop-ups about cookies. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What information do phishers ask for? ","answers":[{"text":"Personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Your position within the company. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Public information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do phishers often ask for in a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"Address details. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Money. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Your mobile phone number. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of these threats could you typically encounter in a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"'If you do not change your login details within 24 hours, you will no longer have access.' ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"'Your current password is 2 months old; change it within 7 days.' ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"'If you do not pay the invoice within 30 days, additional administration costs will be charged.' ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is a message that appears to be from the government a phishing attack? ","answers":[{"text":"When it tells you that there is information ready for you online. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When it asks for personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When it tells you that your passport has expired and you have to apply for a new one. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of message suggests that it is a phishing attack? ","answers":[{"text":"A message about a document that has expired. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"An advertising message from a company that you haven't bought anything from for a long time. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A message with an invoice for a product that you've never bought. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Through which of the following characteristics can you recognize phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"A message about a lottery with which you can win a world tour. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A message with an offer for a trial subscription. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A message that there will be maintenance on the intranet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do with an email when you think it is phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Delete the email immediately so that I do not get malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Forward the email to the responsible person or department, so that the sender can be blocked. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Send an email to my colleagues to warn them about the phishing email so that they do not click on the link. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect yourself from phishing over the internet? ","answers":[{"text":"By making bookmarks for frequently used websites. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By only visiting known websites. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By checking the safety label on the website. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You receive an email from a webshop you have not placed an order with. The webshop asks you to enter your customer details again. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Check whether the email contains signs of phishing and click on the link if the email appears to be safe. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Click the link. I've received emails from this webshop before, so I know that the link is safe. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Go to my webshop account and check that my details are correct. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How can you protect your data against the effects of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"By storing my data in the cloud. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making backups. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By not sending my data via email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect yourself against the consequences of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"By only using software that comes from the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By only using free software that is familiar to me. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using security software. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You are logged in as an administrator and use the internet. Is this safe? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because the firewall protects against the effects of phishing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because phishers mainly focus on people with administrator rights. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because you are more vulnerable to the consequences of phishing. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "baseline-test-i-physical-security":[{"question":"What do you protect with physical security? ","answers":[{"text":"The organization's assets. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The organization's assets and information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The organization's people, assets, and information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What does physical security contribute to? ","answers":[{"text":"The continuity of the organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The culture within the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The professional development of the employees. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does physical security consist of? ","answers":[{"text":"Only of measures. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Of measures and incident responses. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only of incident responses. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of threats does physical security especially focus on? ","answers":[{"text":"People who consciously cause damage. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"People who accidentally cause damage. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"External factors that cause damage. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is physical security an important part of? ","answers":[{"text":"Software development. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Risk analysis. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Information security. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is physical security important for our information? ","answers":[{"text":"Without it, our information is public. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because technical security alone is not enough. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Without it, you do not have access to your own information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do with an access badge to contribute to physical security? ","answers":[{"text":"Ensure that everyone can see you are wearing your access badge. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Ensure that you keep your access badge in a safe place after you have entered the building. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ensure that your access badge only grants you access to your workspaces. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can you do with your access badge? ","answers":[{"text":"Use it for yourself and others and lend it to people you trust. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use it for yourself and others, as long as you do not lend it to anyone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only use it for yourself. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who should be aware when you have an appointment with a visitor? ","answers":[{"text":"Only you. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You and your manager. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You and the reception desk. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you do when you have visitors? ","answers":[{"text":"Accompany them during their visit. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Show them the way to where they should be. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ask them if you should accompany them or if they know the way. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should visitors know about using their visitor's badge? ","answers":[{"text":"That they only have to show it when security asks them. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That they should always wear it where it can easily be seen. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That they only have to use it if no-one else can open the doors. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do if you see strangers walking around unaccompanied or without access badges? ","answers":[{"text":"Take them to reception or to the person they are visiting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Lend them your access badge and get another one for yourself. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Send them away. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do before leaving your workspace? ","answers":[{"text":"Turn off your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lock your computer. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Make sure a colleague keeps an eye on your computer. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "baseline-test-i-risk-management":[{"question":"What is the purpose of risk management? ","answers":[{"text":"To prevent financial and reputational damage, and to guarantee business continuity. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To prevent financial and reputational damage, and to eliminate all risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To prevent financial damage, assure business continuity, and eliminate all risks. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When should you implement risk management? ","answers":[{"text":"Continually. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Once a week. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When incidents occur. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does risk management achieve? ","answers":[{"text":"It gives an advantage over competitors. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It prevents risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It is a good preparation for risks. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What answer best describes risk management? ","answers":[{"text":"Risk prevention. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Dealing with risks. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Protection from risks. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the role of the risk manager? ","answers":[{"text":"Toavoidrisks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To set up regulations that determine what risks the organization is addressing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Provide advice on controlling risks. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What does the risk manager need to assist in managing risks? ","answers":[{"text":"Information from colleagues. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Solutions for risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Permission from the director. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do we have a risk manager? ","answers":[{"text":"For consultation and making decisions. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To answer questions and for support. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To identify risks and develop solutions. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a risk? ","answers":[{"text":"Something that protects the company from making mistakes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Something that interferes with the continuity of the work. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Something you must avoid. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the first step to take when you want to signal risks at work? ","answers":[{"text":"Count risks that occur more often. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ask the risk manager to carry out an audit. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Identify risks. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"There is a risk that someone unintentionally deletes business information. What can cause this? ","answers":[{"text":"The person had wrong access rights. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The person did not have a strong password. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The person was working in a public area. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you prevent by locking your computer screen? ","answers":[{"text":"The computer using too much electricity. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Unauthorized persons viewing information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Someone stealing the computer. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is one of your responsibilities in dealing with risks? ","answers":[{"text":"Provide binding advice on controlling risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Risk prevention. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Identify negative business impact. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is one of your responsibilities in dealing with risks? ","answers":[{"text":"Provide advice on controlling risks. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Tackling high-impact risks yourself. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Understand how likely it is that an incident will occur. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you know about a risk in order to deal with it well? ","answers":[{"text":"How big the possible consequences of the risk are. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"How many causes the risk has. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Who discovered the risk. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You see that multiple colleagues in your department keep their passwords and other sensitive information on post-its. Which approach should you use to deal with this risk? ","answers":[{"text":"Avoid: prohibit the use of post-its for sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Reduce: employees may use a maximum of one post-it with sensitive information per screen. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Share: get your colleagues to censure each other when they write restricted information on post-its. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You decide to reduce the risk of unauthorized persons entering your workspace. What is the correct way to do so? ","answers":[{"text":"Prohibit visitors from entering the building. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Have all visitors escorted after they enter the building. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Take out insurance against loss or theft by visitors. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When should you contact the risk manager? ","answers":[{"text":"When your organization faces more than four risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you have developed a solution for a risk. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you are in doubt about what you should do concerning a specific risk. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When should a risk manager expect you to contact them? ","answers":[{"text":"For every risk you face. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you are facing a risk that could have a major impact on the company. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you have decided how you will manage a certain risk. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "test-information-security":[{"question":"What is the main reason for taking information security measures? ","answers":[{"text":"To meet the expectations of customers and clients. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To prevent unauthorized access to sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To know for sure that you have the right information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is sensitive information? ","answers":[{"text":"Only confidential information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"All business information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"All non-public information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who can you share sensitive information with? ","answers":[{"text":"Within the organization, you can share sensitive information with all those who request it. However, people from outside the organization are not permitted to receive such information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may only share sensitive information with those who are authorized to receive it. This applies both within and outside the organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Within the organization, you may share sensitive information with all those who request it. People who work outside of the organization must be authorized to receive this data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"If you must share sensitive business information, what is the best way to do so? ","answers":[{"text":"Through a secure channel that has been approved by the organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Through the method you are most comfortable with and that you personally trust. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Through your business email address, which will keep the transfer of this information secure. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a safe way to handle business information? ","answers":[{"text":"Don't work offline. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Don't let others look at your screen. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Don't make information digitally available. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What information about the organization or customers is it safe to share on social media? ","answers":[{"text":"Negative information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Public information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Confidential information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How should you organize your work and your private life in order to protect business information? ","answers":[{"text":"You must keep your work and your private life separate. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You must keep your work and your private life separate only on social media. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It doesn't matter. You just have to keep track of things yourself. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is an important characteristic of a working environment in which you can work safely with business information? ","answers":[{"text":"It is fitting for the activities you perform. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It is fitting for the number of colleagues you work with. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It is fitting for the items you need to do your work. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the best place to discuss sensitive information? ","answers":[{"text":"In an area where there are no strangers. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"At home. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In an area where you are alone with your conversation partner. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How quickly should you report actual or potential incidents? ","answers":[{"text":"Within 24 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within 1 hour. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Immediately. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements is true? ","answers":[{"text":"You should only report an incident if it has led to negative consequences. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You should report all actual and potential incidents. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only people involved in an incident should report this. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Who should you report incidents to? ","answers":[{"text":"To someone you fully trust. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To colleagues who work where the incident took place. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To the responsible person or department. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is it important to report incidents and potential incidents? ","answers":[{"text":"So that the culprit can solve the incident. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"So the organization can take appropriate measures. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"So the effects of the security measures are clear. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How many characters should a strong password have at minimum? ","answers":[{"text":"8 characters. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"12 characters. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"16 characters. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should a strong password consist of? ","answers":[{"text":"A random combination of letters and numbers. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Uppercase letters, lowercase letters, numbers, and symbols. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A random combination of at least three types of characters. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How often do you need to change a strong password to protect it? ","answers":[{"text":"Once a year. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Once every 6 months. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Once every 2 months. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the best way to protect the passwords of different accounts? ","answers":[{"text":"Use a different password for each account. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Use different passwords for private accounts and business accounts. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use the same password for each account but add a different serial number. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you work safely with a strong password? ","answers":[{"text":"By only sharing the password with other people in extreme cases. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By never sharing the password with other people. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By changing the password immediately after sharing it with someone. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You are working with sensitive information on your computer. What is the best way to secure this information when briefly leaving your workspace? ","answers":[{"text":"Lock your computer. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Turn the computer screen off. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ask if someone will watch your computer. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a safe way to store sensitive information? ","answers":[{"text":"You and two others agree where to store it. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You store it in a fixed place. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You store it under lock and key. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Where should you dispose of documents containing sensitive information if you don't need them anymore? ","answers":[{"text":"In a paper shredder or a random wastepaper bin. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a random wastepaper bin or a sealed wastepaper bin. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a sealed wastepaper bin or a paper shredder. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about sensitive information in a meeting room is true? ","answers":[{"text":"You must take sensitive information with you when you leave a meeting room. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You are not allowed to bring sensitive information with you to a meeting room. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Sensitive information in a meeting room is safe as long as you lock the door. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What safety measures should you take when arranging to receive a visitor? ","answers":[{"text":"Inform your supervisor of the visit. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Inform reception of the visit. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Inform a colleague of the visit. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How should you handle visitors to your office? ","answers":[{"text":"You escort visitors when they are on the premises. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You give visitors a map of the premises showing the route to your office. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You have your meeting close to the building entrance so that visitors can easily find their way. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"It is wise to give visitors a visitor's badge. What is important in this regard for information security? ","answers":[{"text":"That they keep the badge for emergency situations. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That they wear the badge where it can easily be seen. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Nothing; it is only important that they have a badge. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Every organization receives visitors. As an employee, what should you be aware of? ","answers":[{"text":"That you don't discuss work matters in the hallway, even if it is public information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you keep your office door locked even when you are in the office. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you wear your access badge where it can easily be seen, even when no visitors are present. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you do if you see unknown people alone or without an access badge in the building? ","answers":[{"text":"Ignore them, but report the situation as an incident. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Show them out of the building. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Take them to reception or to the person they are visiting. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which signal of phishing has been described correctly? ","answers":[{"text":"If the mail contains a question about account information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"If the mail contains a hyperlink. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"If the mail has an attachment. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Is it safe to open an attachment from an unknown sender? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, but only if your security software is up to date. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, unless the attachment seems important. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you check first if you want to know whether an email you have received is safe or not? ","answers":[{"text":"Whether the sender has a trusted email address. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Whether you have received an email from this sender before. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Whether the sender has sent the email at a logical time. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"If you know how to handle email securely, where would you NEVER send an email? ","answers":[{"text":"To email addresses of unknown people. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To email addresses you do not trust. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To email addresses of people you have never been in contact with. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is important to email safely? ","answers":[{"text":"That you make sure the email subject matches the content. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you check that you are sending information to the correct person. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That you only send emails from your business account. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a safe way to check whether a link would take you to the mentioned website? ","answers":[{"text":"Clicking the link. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Going to the website using a private window in your browser. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Hovering your mouse over the link. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you do if you receive an email containing a potential threat? ","answers":[{"text":"Report this to the responsible person or department. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Forward the email to your colleagues, adding a warning message. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Mark the email as spam and delete it. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a secure way of printing documents? ","answers":[{"text":"Only have documents printed by your receptionist or assistant. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Remove documents from the printer immediately after printing. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only print classified documents. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following measures ensures that printing documents is safe? ","answers":[{"text":"Using a business printer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Classifying the documents. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Protecting printing with a password. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What does a VPN do? ","answers":[{"text":"It secures your network with a password. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It ensures that others cannot access files on your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It protects your internet traffic from bad influences from the outside world. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you do with mobile devices when you're working outside the office? ","answers":[{"text":"Turn them off, if not in use. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Keep them with you. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Store them in a locked bag or suitcase. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do to keep company information and equipment safe? ","answers":[{"text":"Set a password on your devices. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only use company information and equipment when in the office. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only store company information on the organization's equipment. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do when using mobile devices outside the office? ","answers":[{"text":"Turn them off while travelling. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Protect them with two strong passwords. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lock them when they're not in use. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is important when working with business information outside the office? ","answers":[{"text":"You may only save and edit this information according to company guidelines. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You may only view (and not save or edit) this information when you are outside the office, because saving and editing is not always safe. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you need permission from your supervisor to save and edit business information outside the office. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What method will ensure secure internet use outside the office? ","answers":[{"text":"Using mobile internet instead of Wi-Fi networks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only using networks you have used before. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only using secure networks and VPNs. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How should you treat business information and mobile devices when you take them with you in a car? ","answers":[{"text":"You may not leave them behind in the car. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You may only leave them in the trunk of the car. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may not transport business information in the trunk of the car. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "test-gdpr":[{"question":"Who or what suffers major consequences when personal data is lost or stolen? ","answers":[{"text":"The processing organization and the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The supervisory authority and the data subjects. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The data subjects and the processing organization. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What sanction can be imposed on organizations for violating the privacy law? ","answers":[{"text":"For future processing, they need to ask permission from the European Commission beforehand. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They need to pay a large fine. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They need to collect the personal data again if they want to use them after the violation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is the good protection of personal data important when processed in countries outside the EU? ","answers":[{"text":"Because you are no longer the owner of the personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because you can easily misinterpret personal data in other languages. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because those countries do not always offer an adequate level of protection. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about sending personal data to countries outside of the EU is true? ","answers":[{"text":"This is prohibited in accordance with the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"For this, the rules of those countries apply. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"For this, you need to comply with certain conditions. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What does privacy ensure? ","answers":[{"text":"It ensures that our data are not the same as the data of others. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It protects us and our information from others. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It keeps our information secret from others. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why does the GDPR exist? ","answers":[{"text":"To ensure the protection of privacy is the same throughout the EU. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To have the same organization protect privacy throughout the EU. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To ensure that the same measures are applied throughout the EU to protect the privacy of data subjects. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Can different countries in the EU have different rules for the protection of personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"No, the rules in every country are the same. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, countries are free to decide which rules of the GDPR they use. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, countries can make additions or exceptions to certain rules of the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who monitors the proper application of the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"Supervisory authorities. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The local government. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The European Commission. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Only data about someone in combination with a name. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only data that is unique to one particular person. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"All data that directly or indirectly can be linked to someone. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is “special personal data” according to the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"Sensitive data about someone. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Data that can be directly linked to someone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Someone's secrets. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In which situations may you process someone's special personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Only in special situations, for example, with that person's permission. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In the same situations where you may process other personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only if that person is an employee of your organization. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What are examples of special personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Religion and financial data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Biometric data and political preferences. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Health and membership of an association. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the processing of personal data entail? ","answers":[{"text":"Using personal data. On days you do not use them, you do not process them either. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Everything you do with personal data. It does not matter what this is. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Everything from the moment of collecting until the moment of destroying. The destroying itself is not part of the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may you process personal data in accordance with the principle of lawfulness? ","answers":[{"text":"When the data subjects give their permission or when this is necessary for a reason that is stated in the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When this is necessary for a reason that is stated in the GDPR or when you protect the data sufficiently. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you protect the data sufficiently or when the data subjects give their permission. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the principle of purpose limitation work? ","answers":[{"text":"You may only process personal data if you have a clear and valid goal. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you have collected personal data, you must connect them to a clear and valid goal. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may only process personal data if the goal of the organization is the processing of personal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the principle of minimized data processing mean? ","answers":[{"text":"You need to comply with special rules when you process a small amount of personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When organizations process more personal data than is usual in their sector, they need additional permission. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may not process more personal data than is necessary to achieve the processing goals. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What do you need to do to comply with the principle of accuracy? ","answers":[{"text":"Only process personal data if this is allowed in accordance with the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Take all reasonable measures to ensure that the data you process is correct. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only process personal data once you are sure it is correct. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the principle of storage constraints entail? ","answers":[{"text":"That personal data can only be traced back to a specific person as long as this is needed to achieve the processing goals. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That you may only store a certain amount of personal data. The amount depends on the size of the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you may store personal data for a year at the most. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you need to do with personal data in accordance with the principle of integrity and confidentiality? ","answers":[{"text":"You need to protect data with the measures that are stated in the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need approval from the supervisory authority before you may process the data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need to protect data with appropriate technical and organizational measures. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How should you provide data subjects with information about the processing of their personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"In a way that is easy for the processing organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a way that is understandable and easily accessible for the data subjects. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In a way that describes the processing in detail. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast do organizations need to respond when data subjects ask for information? ","answers":[{"text":"As soon as possible, but within one month at the latest. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within one week at the latest. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within10 working days at the latest. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When do data subjects have the right to receive information? ","answers":[{"text":"Whenever you process their personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only when you adjust something in the processing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when you process special personal data about them. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"To what are data subjects entitled? ","answers":[{"text":"To endorse the way organizations protect their data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To decide where organizations store their data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To see what data organizations have regarding them. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should organizations show to data subjects? ","answers":[{"text":"How their system for data processing works. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"What they do with the data of the data subjects. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Whether they process the same data of other data subjects. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast do organizations need to modify or make an addition to personal data in the event of incorrect or incomplete processing? ","answers":[{"text":"Within one month. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within five business days. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"May data subjects ask the processing organizations to delete their data? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, that is always allowed. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless other interests prevail. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, that is not allowed. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Do data subjects have the right to limit the processing of their data? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, but only in certain situations. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, processing cannot be limited. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, only the processing organization may determine whether they want to limit the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When data subjects ask for their personal data, how should organizations provide it to them? ","answers":[{"text":"On paper. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In any way the organization chooses. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a usual way. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When data subjects receive their personal data from an organization, may they pass them on to another organization? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only in certain situations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"To what may data subjects object? ","answers":[{"text":"To the measures that organizations take to protect their personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To the processing of their personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To the outsourcing of the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When data subjects have objected, is an organization obliged to stop the processing? ","answers":[{"text":"No, the organization may decide this themselves. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless the processing goal has not yet been achieved. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless the organization has a compelling, justified reason. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When are data subjects entitled to a personal assessment of their situation in the case of the automated processing of personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When they ask for it. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When a decision has major consequences for them. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When the automated processing uses wrong data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Is the controller obliged to process the personal data himself? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because it is his responsibility. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, he may outsource it to the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, he may outsource it to a processor. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Does the controller have to register all processing activities in writing? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, this is his responsibility. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Yes, but only when he does not outsource the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, the supervisory authority has this register. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the controller need to report a data breach to the supervisory authority when data subjects are at risk? ","answers":[{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 24 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 36 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 72 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What data breaches does the controller need to register? ","answers":[{"text":"All data breaches. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only data breaches that put data subjects at risk. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only data breaches that involve the leakage of special personal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the controller need to inform the data subjects of a data breach if they are at high risk? ","answers":[{"text":"Within 72 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within 24 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is the controller liable for paying damages? ","answers":[{"text":"Always. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only when he does not outsource the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he has not fulfilled his obligations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In what situation do organizations have to designate a data protection officer (DPO)? ","answers":[{"text":"When they process financial data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When they process a lot of special personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they make mistakes during processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the controller ensure that the processing complies with the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"By outsourcing the processing to a certified processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By taking appropriate technical and organizational measures. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By asking for permission from the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may a processor process personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When he guarantees to comply with all the requirements of the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a controller gives his approval. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When he is enlisted as a processor at the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do the controller and the processor need to record their arrangements? ","answers":[{"text":"In a written agreement. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In an oral or a written agreement. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In an agreement with the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What must the processor do when he processes personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Keep a written backup of processes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Keep a written record of the processing activities. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Have the controller approve the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the processor need to report a data breach to the controller when he discovers this? ","answers":[{"text":"Within 72 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within 24 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is the processor liable for damages? ","answers":[{"text":"Only when the controller is not liable. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he caused the damage. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he has not fulfilled his obligations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the best way to store personal data safely? ","answers":[{"text":"Digitally. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Encrypted. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Secured with a password. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may people have access to personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When they work for the controller or the processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When it is necessary for the work or the processing. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they guarantee to handle the data safely. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do you need to have a procedure to test, review, and evaluate measures? ","answers":[{"text":"To determine whether you are still effectively protecting personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To let the processing method be endorsed by the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As this is not effectively possible without a procedure. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good way to protect personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Let the data be processed by the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Store the data digitally. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pseudonymize the data. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "test-phishing":[{"question":"What is phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Looking up personal information on the internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Spreading malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A type of scam. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What information do phishers collect? ","answers":[{"text":"Personal data and access data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Access data only. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Personal data only. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do phishers gather information? ","answers":[{"text":"They search for information about you on social media. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They pretend to be someone else to get information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They break into the corporate network to steal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does a phisher ensure that you carry out certain actions? ","answers":[{"text":"A phisher introduces himself and immediately asks you nicely to provide information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A phisher pretends to be someone else and gets you to perform certain actions. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A phisher gives you a gift, hoping that you will perform a certain action in return. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is it important to prevent phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Because phishing can now also damage the hardware of your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing can have a financial impact on an individual employee. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing occurs more often. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is phishing a threat to organizations? ","answers":[{"text":"Because phishing can cause stress to employees. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing can infect your computer with malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because you no longer have access to the intranet due to phishing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a consequence of phishing that you want to prevent? ","answers":[{"text":"That the phishing email overloads your inbox. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That phishers post sensitive information on social media. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That your organization loses information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What consequence of phishing do you want to prevent? ","answers":[{"text":"That customers lose their confidence in your organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That your organization has to update all its programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That your organization must employ new employees to adequately protect the information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you prevent by being alert to phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Physical threats. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Overloading the server(s). ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Reputational damage. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"At whom are basic phishing emails aimed? ","answers":[{"text":"A specific target group. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A wide audience. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Higher management. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is there a case of spear phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When a phishing email is sent to a small group of people. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a phishing email has an anonymous greeting. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When a large group of people are contacted by phone to obtain certain information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is CEO fraud? ","answers":[{"text":"Finding sensitive information about the management or the board. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Sending emails that seem to come from the management or the board. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Sending emails that seem to come from the finance department. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is spoofing? ","answers":[{"text":"Faking real websites or the emails of a reliable organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Sending mass emails to large organizations. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Hacking reliable organizations via their website. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is vishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When someone asks you by phone to share personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a website asks you to click on a link. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When someone asks you to share personal information via social media. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is smishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When you receive an SMS with a strange photo. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you click on a fake URL on your phone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you receive an SMS with a fake URL. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What kind of phishing mail is an example of whaling? ","answers":[{"text":"A personalized phishing mail that was sent to an employee of the financial department. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A phishing mail that was sent to a large group of board members or directors. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A personalized phishing mail that was sent to a member of the board or director. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"By an anonymous greeting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By language use without spelling mistakes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By a logo of a well-known organization. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can be a characteristic of a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The mail contains an attachment. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The mail contains bad spelling and grammar. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The mail does not have a logo in it. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is an email with a link phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When the link is written out in full. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When the link occurs several times in the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When the URL does not match the link in the text. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You recognize phishing by a misleading domain name. Where in the URL is the domain name? ","answers":[{"text":"After the www. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"After the extension (for example .com). ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Before the first single slash. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the use of HTTP and HTTPS is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Phishing links use HTTP more often than HTTPS. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Phishing links use HTTPS more often than HTTP. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"HTTPS means that the link is not phishing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of pop-ups are a sign of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Pop-ups with images. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pop-ups that ask for login details. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Pop-ups about cookies. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What information do phishers ask for? ","answers":[{"text":"Personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Your position within the company. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Public information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do phishers often ask for in a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"Address details. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Money. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Your mobile phone number. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of these threats could you typically encounter in a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"'If you do not change your login details within 24 hours, you will no longer have access.' ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"'Your current password is 2 months old; change it within 7 days.' ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"'If you do not pay the invoice within 30 days, additional administration costs will be charged.' ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is a message that appears to be from the government a phishing attack? ","answers":[{"text":"When it tells you that there is information ready for you online. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When it asks for personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When it tells you that your passport has expired and you have to apply for a new one. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of message suggests that it is a phishing attack? ","answers":[{"text":"A message about a document that has expired. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"An advertising message from a company that you haven't bought anything from for a long time. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A message with an invoice for a product that you've never bought. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Through which of the following characteristics can you recognize phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"A message about a lottery with which you can win a world tour. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A message with an offer for a trial subscription. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A message that there will be maintenance on the intranet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do with an email when you think it is phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Delete the email immediately so that I do not get malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Forward the email to the responsible person or department, so that the sender can be blocked. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Send an email to my colleagues to warn them about the phishing email so that they do not click on the link. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect yourself from phishing over the internet? ","answers":[{"text":"By making bookmarks for frequently used websites. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By only visiting known websites. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By checking the safety label on the website. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You receive an email from a webshop you have not placed an order with. The webshop asks you to enter your customer details again. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Check whether the email contains signs of phishing and click on the link if the email appears to be safe. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Click the link. I've received emails from this webshop before, so I know that the link is safe. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Go to my webshop account and check that my details are correct. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How can you protect your data against the effects of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"By storing my data in the cloud. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making backups. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By not sending my data via email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect yourself against the consequences of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"By only using software that comes from the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By only using free software that is familiar to me. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using security software. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You are logged in as an administrator and use the internet. Is this safe? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because the firewall protects against the effects of phishing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because phishers mainly focus on people with administrator rights. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because you are more vulnerable to the consequences of phishing. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "test-malware":[{"question":"What is malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Malicious hardware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Malicious software. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Hardware containing a virus. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can malware do? ","answers":[{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems or interrupt this access. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems, interrupt this access, or collect sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about malware is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Malware exists in different forms, including hybrid forms. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Malware exists in different forms. There are no hybrid forms. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Malware only has one form. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Can malware end up on your computer via the internet? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, this often happens. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, malware can only end up on your computer via an infected USB stick. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, malware can only end up on your computer if other people infect it. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What type of software increases the chance of getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Software that was not installed by an ICT professional. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Software that is not up to date. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Software that is freely available on the internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does malware end up on your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By updating free software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using free software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By installing free software that is already infected. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How does malware end up on your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By visiting websites that provide free music or movies and by using an unknown USB stick. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By uploading photos to the cloud or by sending emails. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By connecting your phone to the computer to charge it or by clicking on ads. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does malware greatly affect people or organizations? ","answers":[{"text":"By sending threatening emails or stealing money or personal information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By stealing money or personal information, or preventing you from accessing your device. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By preventing you from accessing your device or sending threatening emails. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do organizations increasingly suffer from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because organizations are more and more dependent on ICT. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because malware is becoming increasingly malicious. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because organizations have more trouble detecting malware. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How far does malware spread if an organization is infected with it? ","answers":[{"text":"It spreads only through the department to which the infected computer belongs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It spreads through the entire company network, but not to other organizations. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It spreads through the entire company network or to other organizations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is a slow computer a sign of malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because the computer can do little or nothing else if it is running malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because the computer is partially broken and therefore does not work fast anymore. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because one purpose of malware is to affect the working memory of the computer. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a sign that you are suffering from a malware infection? ","answers":[{"text":"Websites that show ads. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pop-ups that open spontaneously. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You receive emails with an untrustworthy attachment. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By processes that are running while the computer is turned off. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By unknown security software that shows pop-ups. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By software that you did not install yourself. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What often happens to people who suffer from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Emails are sent in their name. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They receive emails from unknown senders. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They can no longer send attachments via email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you tell that you are suffering from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Your antivirus program or other programs no longer work. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Your antivirus program has suddenly disappeared from your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Programs mimic each other's operations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How come you sometimes do not notice malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because malware is sometimes disabled. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because the signs are not always visible right away. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because you must go on the internet before malware is activated. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do to find out if you have malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Restart your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Look for unknown files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Carry out a malware scan. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Do the organization's security systems protect against malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, they are set up especially for that purpose. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, but that does not guarantee anything. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, malware can easily circumvent security systems. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is your role in preventing malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Remaining alert. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Having my computer checked periodically for signs of malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Changing antivirus programs every year. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect your computer against malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By making sure you have secure hardware and software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making sure you have hardware that is not vulnerable to malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making sure you have software that protects against malware. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you regularly do with your programs to prevent getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Reinstall them. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Make backups. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Run updates. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When do you have the greatest chance of getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"When you are logged in as an administrator. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you work on the same computer a lot. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you have recently installed updates. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What risk do free antivirus programs pose? ","answers":[{"text":"They are bad at detecting malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They sometimes contain malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"There are no updates for them. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you get malware via an email from an unknown or unexpected sender? ","answers":[{"text":"By opening the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By opening the attachment. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By answering the email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which ads have the highest chance of containing malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Ads that seem too good to be true. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Ads that have images. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ads that are only valid for a limited time. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Malware infections can be prevented by not using untrustworthy websites. What is an example of an untrustworthy website? ","answers":[{"text":"A website that you have not visited before. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A website that does not end in .net or .org. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A website offering free downloads. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What type of file should you not download if you want to prevent malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Files from people outside the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Free and/or illegal files. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Files that are larger than 2 GB. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What helps to prevent malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Keeping a backup of your files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Reporting suspicious situations and incidents. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Periodically emptying your email inbox. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you help others to prevent their systems from becoming infected with malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By reporting malware to a fraud helpdesk in your country. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By forwarding suspicious emails to colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You cannot help other people; everyone must pay attention themselves. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you remove malware from your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By searching for the malware file and moving it to the trash can on your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By deleting all downloads and updating your programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By completely erasing your hard disk and reinstalling the system and programs. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Can malware be combatted with system restoration? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"This depends on the situation. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "test-risk-management":[{"question":"What is the purpose of risk management? ","answers":[{"text":"To prevent financial and reputational damage, and to guarantee business continuity. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To prevent financial and reputational damage, and to eliminate all risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To prevent financial damage, assure business continuity, and eliminate all risks. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When should you implement risk management? ","answers":[{"text":"Continually. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Once a week. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When incidents occur. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does risk management achieve? ","answers":[{"text":"It gives an advantage over competitors. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It prevents risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It is a good preparation for risks. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What answer best describes risk management? ","answers":[{"text":"Risk prevention. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Dealing with risks. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Protection from risks. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the role of the risk manager? ","answers":[{"text":"Toavoidrisks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To set up regulations that determine what risks the organization is addressing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Provide advice on controlling risks. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What does the risk manager need to assist in managing risks? ","answers":[{"text":"Information from colleagues. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Solutions for risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Permission from the director. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do we have a risk manager? ","answers":[{"text":"For consultation and making decisions. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To answer questions and for support. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To identify risks and develop solutions. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a risk? ","answers":[{"text":"Something that protects the company from making mistakes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Something that interferes with the continuity of the work. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Something you must avoid. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the first step to take when you want to signal risks at work? ","answers":[{"text":"Count risks that occur more often. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ask the risk manager to carry out an audit. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Identify risks. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"There is a risk that someone unintentionally deletes business information. What can cause this? ","answers":[{"text":"The person had wrong access rights. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The person did not have a strong password. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The person was working in a public area. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you prevent by locking your computer screen? ","answers":[{"text":"The computer using too much electricity. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Unauthorized persons viewing information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Someone stealing the computer. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is one of your responsibilities in dealing with risks? ","answers":[{"text":"Provide binding advice on controlling risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Risk prevention. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Identify negative business impact. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is one of your responsibilities in dealing with risks? ","answers":[{"text":"Provide advice on controlling risks. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Tackling high-impact risks yourself. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Understand how likely it is that an incident will occur. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you know about a risk in order to deal with it well? ","answers":[{"text":"How big the possible consequences of the risk are. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"How many causes the risk has. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Who discovered the risk. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You see that multiple colleagues in your department keep their passwords and other sensitive information on post-its. Which approach should you use to deal with this risk? ","answers":[{"text":"Avoid: prohibit the use of post-its for sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Reduce: employees may use a maximum of one post-it with sensitive information per screen. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Share: get your colleagues to censure each other when they write restricted information on post-its. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You decide to reduce the risk of unauthorized persons entering your workspace. What is the correct way to do so? ","answers":[{"text":"Prohibit visitors from entering the building. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Have all visitors escorted after they enter the building. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Take out insurance against loss or theft by visitors. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When should you contact the risk manager? ","answers":[{"text":"When your organization faces more than four risks. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you have developed a solution for a risk. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you are in doubt about what you should do concerning a specific risk. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When should a risk manager expect you to contact them? ","answers":[{"text":"For every risk you face. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you are facing a risk that could have a major impact on the company. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you have decided how you will manage a certain risk. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "test-cybersecurity":[{"question":"Which of the following statements about cybersecurity is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping physical information secure. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping digital information secure. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping physical and digital information secure. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a possible consequence of a cybersecurity threat? ","answers":[{"text":"We can no longer pay bills. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Employees can no longer contact clients. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Clients, partners, and employees lose trust in the organization. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why do businesses work hard on their cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"Because they often cooperate with other companies. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because a cybersecurity threat can have huge financial consequences. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To conform with the privacy regulations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is cybersecurity important? ","answers":[{"text":"Because incidents can endanger the health and safety of people. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because some incidents cannot be solved. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because this is how you prevent unauthorized access to the office. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does malware threaten cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"By damaging or erasing information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By installing malicious hardware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By automatically opening attachments in phishing emails. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You use the internet in public. When is this a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"When you set up a device as a hotspot. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use mobile internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Is it safe to store information in a public cloud? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, public cloud services are well protected and therefore secure. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because some public cloud services are allowed to access your files. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, because everyone has access to the information in a public cloud. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do IoT devices pose a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"Because they are easy to hack. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because they break easily. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because they tend to lose their connection to the internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do phishers operate? ","answers":[{"text":"They listen in when you are having a confidential discussion in public. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They send emails in which they ask for personal or business information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They search wastepaper bins to find personal or business information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the IoT pose a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"When different devices do not communicate with each other properly, a data leak occurs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you forget your password, it is difficult to access personal information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When default passwords are not changed, hackers can get easy access to sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When do cybercriminals commit spoofing? ","answers":[{"text":"When they replicate a website. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they spread malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When they break into a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The sender is not familiar. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The sender cannot be found on the internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The sender's name does not match the email address. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which characteristics of an email suggest the possibility of a phishing attempt? ","answers":[{"text":"It arrives at night. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It starts with a general greeting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It doesn't have a subject. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The images are not downloaded automatically. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It has an attachment. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It requests personal information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which sentence is a sign of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"'Go to our website to see all offers.' ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"'Click on the link, register and win a free iPad.' ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"'Dear Peter, we have a wonderful offer for you!' ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect your IoT devices? ","answers":[{"text":"By turning off the internet connection whenever it is not needed. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By only connecting the devices with your own Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By only connecting the devices with mobile internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you reduce the risk of infection with malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By regularly making backups of your programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By keeping programs up to date. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By keeping new programs in the downloads folder. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why should you make regular backups? ","answers":[{"text":"To secure information in the event of a crash or a malware infection. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To keep information available to all your colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To keep information available when you are offline. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When does an antivirus program have to be enabled? ","answers":[{"text":"Only when you suspect a threat. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"At least once a day. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Always. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is your use of the IoT secure? ","answers":[{"text":"When you use the same strong password for each device. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use a different strong password for each device. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you use the default password for each device, because it is a strong password. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You have a new IoT device. In what way do you change the login information? ","answers":[{"text":"You change the default username to your email address. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You use the password that is given in the user manual. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You change the default password to a new strong password. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You receive a request via email to send personal information. What is the best thing to do? ","answers":[{"text":"Check whether the sender is allowed to receive the information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Do not provide the information and delete the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Send the requested information, but also ask for an explanation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You receive a suspicious email. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Delete the email and notify your immediate colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Notify the responsible person or department. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Block the sender and delete the email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good way to remember your passwords? ","answers":[{"text":"Write them down in a password logbook. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Keep them in a secured Excel file. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use a password manager. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is two-factor authentication? ","answers":[{"text":"The protection of your login information with two different strong passwords. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The protection of your login information with a strong password and a one-time code, a fingerprint, a hard token, etc. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The protection of your login information with a password in which you have used at least two different types of characters. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the most secure way to use the internet in public? ","answers":[{"text":"Using a secure Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using mobile internet. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why should you use a VPN when using public internet? ","answers":[{"text":"A VPN stops phishing emails. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A VPN blocks infected ads. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A VPN encrypts all information that you send. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why should you remove cookies regularly? ","answers":[{"text":"Cookies follow you around the internet. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Cookies spread malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cookies slow down your internet speed. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the privacy settings of social media accounts is true? ","answers":[{"text":"They can barely be changed, which makes your information visible to everyone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They are often automatically set to “public”, which makes your information visible to everyone. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They are often automatically set to “private”, which makes your information invisible to strangers. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good practice when using social media? ","answers":[{"text":"Giving serious thought to posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Checking your privacy settings before posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Not posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is a good way to protect your online privacy? ","answers":[{"text":"Using an ad blocker in your browser. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Not using social media at work. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using an antivirus program. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good step toward making mobile devices criminal-proof? ","answers":[{"text":"Install the latest software version. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Disable the location features of your device. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Set up a strong password or biometric recognition. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "test-physical-security":[{"question":"What do you protect with physical security? ","answers":[{"text":"The organization's assets. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The organization's assets and information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The organization's people, assets, and information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What does physical security contribute to? ","answers":[{"text":"The continuity of the organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The culture within the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The professional development of the employees. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does physical security consist of? ","answers":[{"text":"Only of measures. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Of measures and incident responses. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only of incident responses. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of threats does physical security especially focus on? ","answers":[{"text":"People who consciously cause damage. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"People who accidentally cause damage. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"External factors that cause damage. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is physical security an important part of? ","answers":[{"text":"Software development. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Risk analysis. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Information security. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is physical security important for our information? ","answers":[{"text":"Without it, our information is public. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because technical security alone is not enough. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Without it, you do not have access to your own information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do with an access badge to contribute to physical security? ","answers":[{"text":"Ensure that everyone can see you are wearing your access badge. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Ensure that you keep your access badge in a safe place after you have entered the building. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ensure that your access badge only grants you access to your workspaces. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can you do with your access badge? ","answers":[{"text":"Use it for yourself and others and lend it to people you trust. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use it for yourself and others, as long as you do not lend it to anyone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only use it for yourself. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who should be aware when you have an appointment with a visitor? ","answers":[{"text":"Only you. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You and your manager. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You and the reception desk. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you do when you have visitors? ","answers":[{"text":"Accompany them during their visit. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Show them the way to where they should be. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ask them if you should accompany them or if they know the way. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should visitors know about using their visitor's badge? ","answers":[{"text":"That they only have to show it when security asks them. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That they should always wear it where it can easily be seen. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That they only have to use it if no-one else can open the doors. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do if you see strangers walking around unaccompanied or without access badges? ","answers":[{"text":"Take them to reception or to the person they are visiting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Lend them your access badge and get another one for yourself. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Send them away. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do before leaving your workspace? ","answers":[{"text":"Turn off your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Lock your computer. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Make sure a colleague keeps an eye on your computer. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "test-information-classification":[{"question":"What is the primary reason why you should follow information classification regulations? ","answers":[{"text":"Because then unknown persons cannot access my personal files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Information is essential to our organization. If we follow the rules, we ensure the availability, integrity and confidentiality of the information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Severe penalties can be imposed by the organization on those who do not comply with information classification regulations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of these statements about public information is correct? ","answers":[{"text":"Public information is intended for the general public. It includes marketing materials such as flyers and posters. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Public information is intended for the general public. It includes personal information of the company's employees. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Public information is not intended for the general public. It includes information about new projects. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is it so important that each piece of information is classified correctly? ","answers":[{"text":"To ensure that the desired levels of confidentiality, integrity, and availability of this information are ensured. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To ensure that there are not too many security measures, which would be hugely expensive. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Both statements are correct. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"A colleague calls you and asks for information regarding a recent project. You've worked on this project, but he hasn't. Are you allowed to share this information? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because it is always safe to share information about projects with a colleague. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, but only if the information is classified as “internal” or “confidential”. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, but only if the information is classified as “public” or “internal”. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When confidential information is no longer needed, you should throw it in a waste bin. Is this correct? ","answers":[{"text":"That's not correct. Confidential information should go through a shredder when it is no longer needed. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That is correct. The information is no longer used, and nobody will be interested in it. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That is correct. It is not a problem to throw information in the trash, as it is emptied every night by the cleaning staff. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the correct order of information classification categories? ","answers":[{"text":"Internal, confidential, secret, public. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Public, internal, confidential, secret. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Public, confidential, internal, secret. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you ensure that the information you are working with maintains the correct classification? ","answers":[{"text":"Only share information with people I know and who are authorized to receive it. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Share information only within the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Be familiar with the classification levels and share the information accordingly. Possibly ask the owner if the rating level does not seem to be correct. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What kind of business information can you share with people you don't know? ","answers":[{"text":"Company telephone numbers and email addresses only. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only unclassified/public information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You are not allowed to provide any information to strangers at all. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "test-working-in-the-cloud":[{"question":"What risks should you be aware of when working with a public cloud service? ","answers":[{"text":"The cloud service supplier may have access to the contents of the files placed in the cloud. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you might not always be able to access your files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Both answers above are risks. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"If you are considering using a cloud service for business information, what can you use? ","answers":[{"text":"Google Docs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Dropbox. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Any cloud service, as long as it has been approved by the organization. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the applications below are examples of cloud services? ","answers":[{"text":"WhatsApp, Photoshop, Evernote, Facebook, WeTransfer, and Windows Media Player. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"WhatsApp, Google Translate, OneDrive, Facebook, WeTransfer, and Gmail. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"WhatsApp, Google Translate, Evernote, LinkedIn, WeTransfer, and Word. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"A new project has been launched. Because sensitive data will be used, it has been decided to use a private cloud for editing and storing data. What does that mean? ","answers":[{"text":"The services and the hardware will be exclusively used by your company. They can be hosted by your own IT department or by an external service. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A colleague installs the servers in a specially equipped, air-conditioned room in his house. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The data in a private cloud is available only to you and is stored on servers located in your own IT department. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You have worked on a project with a group of colleagues and have stored files containing sensitive information in the cloud. You have to make sure that all files are deleted and no longer accessible. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"I contact the service provider and request that the files be permanently deleted. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"I ask the project leader with the highest permissions to delete the files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"I remove the files myself. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Who is the owner of data stored in the cloud? ","answers":[{"text":"The company that stores the data owns the intellectual property rights. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The hosting provider, because the data is stored on their hardware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"This depends on the contractual agreements between the company and the hosting provider. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which statement about public cloud services is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Public cloud services are often not safe enough for the processing of personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Public cloud services have regulations that prohibit them from accessing your information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Your own organization is responsible for the protection of company information in the cloud. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which statement is correct? ","answers":[{"text":"If confidential information is encrypted and the recipient is a supplier of your organization that has made agreements regarding the handling of confidential information, this information may be shared through a public cloud service. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"If I send work files to my Gmail account, I can continue to work on it safely when I get home. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"If I use a public cloud service from an American supplier, my files will also be stored in the US. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "test-mobile-devices":[{"question":"How can you ensure that data stored on your mobile device(s) does not end up in the wrong hands? ","answers":[{"text":"Link the mobile devices to a cloud service. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Protect your mobile devices with a PIN. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Enable the mobile device function that allows it to be searched for remotely. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Are there risks associated with a public cloud service, such as Dropbox? ","answers":[{"text":"No, because without the internet you also have no access to your files in the cloud. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, you may no longer be the owner of your own files. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Yes, but there is no risk if you use a strong password. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do in the event of an incident involving your mobile device? ","answers":[{"text":"First find out how you can solve it yourself. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Immediately report to the responsible department. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Not report if it is your own device. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Are there any risks associated with working with mobile equipment in public areas? ","answers":[{"text":"No, because you always keep your mobile devices close to you. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because the responsible department has protected your mobile devices well. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, because other people present could easily be looking at your screen. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Is it safe to connect your mobile devices to public Wi-Fi networks? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because you've installed antivirus software on all your devices. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, because public networks are also secure. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because this increases the risk of a hacker attack. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is it important to keep business and private lives separate when using social media on mobile devices? ","answers":[{"text":"To prevent your opinion being regarded as the opinion of the organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To prevent you sending a business email to one of your personal contacts. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To prevent your employer from seeing what you do at weekends. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you pay attention to when working with your mobile device in the cloud? ","answers":[{"text":"You should never place any business information in a public cloud. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You can put business files in Dropbox, provided the files are encrypted. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You do not need to pay attention to anything, as the responsible department ensures that you can work safely. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why should mobile devices be protected by a password? ","answers":[{"text":"To prevent them from being stolen. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To prevent them from being infected with a virus. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To prevent unauthorized people from gaining access to the information on the devices or via the network. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "test-social-engineering":[{"question":"Someone you don't know calls and asks for information about a recent project. Is it safe to share this information? ","answers":[{"text":"Only if this person asks specific questions related to the project and seems trustworthy. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You should never share sensitive information with people you do not know. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only if the person claims that he really needs the information because he has to work on this project as well. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You accept a gift from a business contact. How is this related to social engineering? ","answers":[{"text":"It isn't related to social engineering. Social engineers are criminals; normal business contacts do not pose a threat. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The business contact could be a social engineer trying to create an atmosphere in which you are more likely to give information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Accepting a gift makes you feel obligated to return the favor. That's why you should never accept a gift from a business contact. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the risk of social engineering relate to other information security risks? ","answers":[{"text":"Social engineering is a relatively crude type of attack compared to the advanced methods that hackers use. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"General information security risks can put the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of information at risk, whereas social engineering only puts the confidentiality of information at risk. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Social engineering is one of the most important information security risks. The methods are often carried out alongside advanced technical methods. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"A new colleague is waiting for a user account and cannot start working in the meantime. The colleague asks you for your login information. Are you allowed to give her your login name and password?<strong><br /></strong> ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. This is a temporary situation and is therefore allowed. After the colleague has received a new account, you must change your password. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. The colleague might not have the same authorization to access systems and information as you. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It depends. You are allowed to share a password that gives access to basic resources (intranet or a text formatting application), but not a password that gives access to confidential systems. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"A member of the cleaning staff asks you to open a locked office in order to clean it. Assuming you have a key, should you do this? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. This is an efficient solution and means that everyone can keep working. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It depends on the type of information and device(s) in the office. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. They must have their own keys. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Someone higher up in the organization asks you for a specific piece of information. Should you give it? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. You must comply with the requests of people higher up in the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only if this person is authorized to have that information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only if the information is not classified. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Sending an email to someone requesting a small investment in exchange for a large reward. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Sending an email that contains a malicious piece of software able to intercept passwords. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Sending an email asking the recipient to click on a link that asks for passwords or other such restricted information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You recently called the helpdesk. Someone now returns your call. Are you sure this is the helpdesk? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. How would they otherwise know that you just called? ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes. Helpdesk data is very confidential. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. A social engineer can use this ruse. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "test-the-new-way-of-working":[{"question":"You work in a flexible workspace. How do you handle confidential information safely? ","answers":[{"text":"You discuss confidential information behind closed doors. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Ask your supervisor or manager if you are allowed to work with restricted information here. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You work with digital documents instead of paper documents. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"After a day working from home you want to dispose of redundant paperwork that contains confidential information. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Put the papers through a shredder. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Tear up the paper and put it in with the household waste. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Tear up the paper and place it in the wastepaper bin. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of these statements concerning working safely in public is correct? ","answers":[{"text":"You should use a VPN connection if you want to use the internet when you're on your way somewhere. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You should speak as quietly as possible when making confidential phone calls in public. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You should tear up restricted paperwork before putting it in a public trash can. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is an information security risk when working in a flexible workspace? ","answers":[{"text":"It is not always easy to find an available desk in a flexible workspace. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You must always lock your computer when leaving your workspace. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You never know if everyone around you has the same level of access to confidential information as you do. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You are working on a private computer at home. How do you handle confidential information safely? ","answers":[{"text":"You give your partner and children their own user accounts on the computer. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You tell your partner and children not to touch your work-related documents. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You place your private computer in a separate room where you can work without being distracted. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You are at work in a noisy caf�. To call a client, you walk outside. What do you need to do with your laptop? ","answers":[{"text":"Leave the laptop in the caf�; you'll be back in a minute. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Take the laptop with you. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Ask an employee of the caf� to watch your laptop. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You would like to install a new program on your computer. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Install the program and get started. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ask the system administrator to install the program for you. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Install the program and then ask the system administrator if the installation of the program was successful. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a “clean desk”? ","answers":[{"text":"A desk on which there are no bread crumbs or coffee stains. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A desk on which there is no sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A desk without a computer or other electronic devices. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "baseline-test-ii-cybersecurity":[{"question":"Which of the following statements about cybersecurity is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping physical information secure. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping digital information secure. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Cybersecurity is about keeping physical and digital information secure. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following is a possible consequence of a cybersecurity threat? ","answers":[{"text":"We can no longer pay bills. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Employees can no longer contact clients. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Clients, partners, and employees lose trust in the organization. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why do businesses work hard on their cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"Because they often cooperate with other companies. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because a cybersecurity threat can have huge financial consequences. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To conform with the privacy regulations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is cybersecurity important? ","answers":[{"text":"Because incidents can endanger the health and safety of people. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because some incidents cannot be solved. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because this is how you prevent unauthorized access to the office. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does malware threaten cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"By damaging or erasing information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By installing malicious hardware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By automatically opening attachments in phishing emails. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You use the internet in public. When is this a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"When you set up a device as a hotspot. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use mobile internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Is it safe to store information in a public cloud? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, public cloud services are well protected and therefore secure. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because some public cloud services are allowed to access your files. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, because everyone has access to the information in a public cloud. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do IoT devices pose a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"Because they are easy to hack. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because they break easily. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because they tend to lose their connection to the internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do phishers operate? ","answers":[{"text":"They listen in when you are having a confidential discussion in public. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They send emails in which they ask for personal or business information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They search wastepaper bins to find personal or business information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the IoT pose a threat to cybersecurity? ","answers":[{"text":"When different devices do not communicate with each other properly, a data leak occurs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you forget your password, it is difficult to access personal information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When default passwords are not changed, hackers can get easy access to sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When do cybercriminals commit spoofing? ","answers":[{"text":"When they replicate a website. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they spread malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When they break into a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The sender is not familiar. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The sender cannot be found on the internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The sender's name does not match the email address. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which characteristics of an email suggest the possibility of a phishing attempt? ","answers":[{"text":"It arrives at night. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It starts with a general greeting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It doesn't have a subject. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The images are not downloaded automatically. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It has an attachment. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It requests personal information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which sentence is a sign of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"'Go to our website to see all offers.' ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"'Click on the link, register and win a free iPad.' ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"'Dear Peter, we have a wonderful offer for you!' ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect your IoT devices? ","answers":[{"text":"By turning off the internet connection whenever it is not needed. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By only connecting the devices with your own Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By only connecting the devices with mobile internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you reduce the risk of infection with malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By regularly making backups of your programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By keeping programs up to date. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By keeping new programs in the downloads folder. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why should you make regular backups? ","answers":[{"text":"To secure information in the event of a crash or a malware infection. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To keep information available to all your colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To keep information available when you are offline. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When does an antivirus program have to be enabled? ","answers":[{"text":"Only when you suspect a threat. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"At least once a day. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Always. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is your use of the IoT secure? ","answers":[{"text":"When you use the same strong password for each device. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you use a different strong password for each device. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you use the default password for each device, because it is a strong password. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You have a new IoT device. In what way do you change the login information? ","answers":[{"text":"You change the default username to your email address. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You use the password that is given in the user manual. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You change the default password to a new strong password. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You receive a request via email to send personal information. What is the best thing to do? ","answers":[{"text":"Check whether the sender is allowed to receive the information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Do not provide the information and delete the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Send the requested information, but also ask for an explanation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You receive a suspicious email. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Delete the email and notify your immediate colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Notify the responsible person or department. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Block the sender and delete the email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good way to remember your passwords? ","answers":[{"text":"Write them down in a password logbook. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Keep them in a secured Excel file. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Use a password manager. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is two-factor authentication? ","answers":[{"text":"The protection of your login information with two different strong passwords. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The protection of your login information with a strong password and a one-time code, a fingerprint, a hard token, etc. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The protection of your login information with a password in which you have used at least two different types of characters. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is the most secure way to use the internet in public? ","answers":[{"text":"Using a secure Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using a public Wi-Fi network. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using mobile internet. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why should you use a VPN when using public internet? ","answers":[{"text":"A VPN stops phishing emails. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A VPN blocks infected ads. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A VPN encrypts all information that you send. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why should you remove cookies regularly? ","answers":[{"text":"Cookies follow you around the internet. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Cookies spread malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Cookies slow down your internet speed. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the privacy settings of social media accounts is true? ","answers":[{"text":"They can barely be changed, which makes your information visible to everyone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They are often automatically set to “public”, which makes your information visible to everyone. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They are often automatically set to “private”, which makes your information invisible to strangers. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good practice when using social media? ","answers":[{"text":"Giving serious thought to posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Checking your privacy settings before posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Not posting sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is a good way to protect your online privacy? ","answers":[{"text":"Using an ad blocker in your browser. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Not using social media at work. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Using an antivirus program. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good step toward making mobile devices criminal-proof? ","answers":[{"text":"Install the latest software version. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Disable the location features of your device. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Set up a strong password or biometric recognition. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "baseline-test-ii-gdpr":[{"question":"How should you provide data subjects with information about the processing of their personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"In a way that is easy for the processing organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a way that is understandable and easily accessible for the data subjects. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In a way that describes the processing in detail. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast do organizations need to respond when data subjects ask for information? ","answers":[{"text":"As soon as possible, but within one month at the latest. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Within one month. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within one week. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When do data subjects have the right to receive information? ","answers":[{"text":"Whenever you process their personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only when you adjust something in the processing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when you process special personal data about them. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"To what are data subjects entitled? ","answers":[{"text":"To endorse the way organizations protect their data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To decide where organizations store their data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To see what data organizations have regarding them. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should organizations show to data subjects? ","answers":[{"text":"How their system for data processing works. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"What they do with the data of the data subjects. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Whether they process the same data of other data subjects. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast do organizations need to modify or make an addition to personal data in the event of incorrect or incomplete processing? ","answers":[{"text":"Within one month. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within five business days. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"May data subjects ask the processing organizations to delete their data? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, that is always allowed. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless other interests prevail. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, that is not allowed. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Do data subjects have the right to limit the processing of their data? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, but only in certain situations. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, processing cannot be limited. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, only the processing organization may determine whether they want to limit the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When data subjects ask for their personal data, how should organizations provide it to them? ","answers":[{"text":"On paper. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In any way the organization chooses. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In a usual way. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When data subjects receive their personal data from an organization, may they pass them on to another organization? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only in certain situations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"To what may data subjects object? ","answers":[{"text":"To the measures that organizations take to protect their personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To the processing of their personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To the outsourcing of the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When data subjects have objected, is an organization obliged to stop the processing? ","answers":[{"text":"No, the organization may decide this themselves. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless the processing goal has not yet been achieved. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, unless the organization has a compelling, justified reason. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When are data subjects entitled to a personal assessment of their situation in the case of the automated processing of personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When they ask for it. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When a decision has major consequences for them. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When the automated processing uses wrong data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Is the controller obliged to process the personal data himself? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because it is his responsibility. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, he may outsource it to the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, he may outsource it to a processor. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Does the controller have to register all processing activities in writing? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, this is his responsibility. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Yes, but only when he does not outsource the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, the supervisory authority has this register. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the controller need to report a data breach to the supervisory authority when data subjects are at risk? ","answers":[{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 24 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 36 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible, but within 72 hours after discovery at the latest. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What data breaches does the controller need to register? ","answers":[{"text":"All data breaches. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only data breaches that put data subjects at risk. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only data breaches that involve the leakage of special personal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the controller need to inform the data subjects of a data breach if they are at high risk? ","answers":[{"text":"Within 72 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within 24 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is the controller liable for paying damages? ","answers":[{"text":"Always. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only when he does not outsource the processing to a processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he has not fulfilled his obligations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In what situation do organizations have to designate a data protection officer (DPO)? ","answers":[{"text":"When they process financial data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When they process a lot of special personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they make mistakes during processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the controller ensure that the processing complies with the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"By outsourcing the processing to a certified processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By taking appropriate technical and organizational measures. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By asking for permission from the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may a processor process personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When he guarantees to comply with all the requirements of the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a controller gives his approval. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When he is enlisted as a processor at the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do the controller and the processor need to record their arrangements? ","answers":[{"text":"In a written agreement. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In an oral or a written agreement. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"In an agreement with the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What must the processor do when he processes personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Keep a written backup of processes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Keep a written record of the processing activities. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Have the controller approve the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How fast does the processor need to report a data breach to the controller when he discovers this? ","answers":[{"text":"Within 72 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Within 24 hours. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As soon as possible. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When is the processor liable for damages? ","answers":[{"text":"Only when the controller is not liable. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he caused the damage. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only when he has not fulfilled his obligations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the best way to store personal data safely? ","answers":[{"text":"Digitally. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Encrypted. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Secured with a password. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may people have access to personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"When they work for the controller or the processor. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When it is necessary for the work or the processing. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When they guarantee to handle the data safely. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do you need to have a procedure to test, review, and evaluate measures? ","answers":[{"text":"To determine whether you are still effectively protecting personal data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To let the processing method be endorsed by the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"As this is not effectively possible without a procedure. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a good way to protect personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Let the data be processed by the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Store the data digitally. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pseudonymize the data. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who or what suffers major consequences when personal data is lost or stolen? ","answers":[{"text":"The processing organization and the supervisory authority. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The supervisory authority and the data subjects. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The data subjects and the processing organization. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What sanction can be imposed on organizations for violating the privacy law? ","answers":[{"text":"For future processing, they need to ask permission from the European Commission beforehand. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They need to pay a large fine. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They need to collect the personal data again if they want to use them after the violation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is the good protection of personal data important when processed in countries outside the EU? ","answers":[{"text":"Because you are no longer the owner of the personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because you can easily misinterpret personal data in other languages. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because those countries do not always offer an adequate level of protection. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is the largest fine for organizations that violate the law? ","answers":[{"text":"�20 million or 4% of the total worldwide annual turnover. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"�10 million or 4% of the total worldwide annual turnover. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"�10 million or 2% of the total worldwide annual turnover. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about sending personal data to countries outside of the EU is true? ","answers":[{"text":"This is prohibited in accordance with the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"For this, the rules of those countries apply. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"For this, you need to comply with certain conditions. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Only data about someone in combination with a name. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only data that is unique to one particular person. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"All data that directly or indirectly can be linked to someone. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What is “special personal data” according to the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"Sensitive data about someone. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Data that can be directly linked to someone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Someone's secrets. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"In which situations may you process someone's special personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Only in special situations, for example, with that person's permission. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"In the same situations where you may process other personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Only if that person is an employee of your organization. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What are examples of special personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"Religion and financial data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Biometric data and political preferences. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Health and membership of an association. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the processing of personal data entail? ","answers":[{"text":"Using personal data. On days you do not use them, you do not process them either. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Everything you do with personal data. It does not matter what this is. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Everything from the moment of collecting until the moment of destroying. The destroying itself is not part of the processing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does privacy ensure? ","answers":[{"text":"It ensures that our data are not the same as the data of others. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It protects us and our information from others. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"It keeps our information secret from others. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why was the GDPR implemented? ","answers":[{"text":"To ensure the protection of privacy is the same throughout the EU. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"To have the same organization protect privacy throughout the EU. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"To ensure that the same measures are applied throughout the EU to protect the privacy of data subjects. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Can different countries in the EU have different rules for the protection of personal data? ","answers":[{"text":"No, the rules in every country are the same. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, countries are free to decide which rules of the GDPR they use. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, countries can make additions or exceptions to certain rules of the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Who monitors the proper application of the GDPR? ","answers":[{"text":"Supervisory authorities. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The local government. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The European Commission. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When may you process personal data in accordance with the principle of lawfulness? ","answers":[{"text":"When the data subjects give their permission or when this is necessary for a reason that is stated in the GDPR. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When this is necessary for a reason that is stated in the GDPR or when you protect the data sufficiently. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you protect the data sufficiently or when the data subjects give their permission. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does the principle of purpose limitation work? ","answers":[{"text":"You may only process personal data if you have a clear and valid goal. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you have collected personal data, you must connect them to a clear and valid goal. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may only process personal data if the goal of the organization is the processing of personal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the principle of minimized data processing mean? ","answers":[{"text":"You need to comply with special rules when you process a small amount of personal data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When organizations process more personal data than is usual in their sector, they need additional permission. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You may not process more personal data than is necessary to achieve the processing goals. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What do you need to do to comply with the principle of accuracy? ","answers":[{"text":"Only process personal data if this is allowed in accordance with the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Take all reasonable measures to ensure that the data you process is correct. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Only process personal data once you are sure it is correct. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What does the principle of storage constraints entail? ","answers":[{"text":"That personal data can only be traced back to a specific person as long as this is needed to achieve the processing goals. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That you may only store a certain amount of personal data. The amount depends on the size of the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That you may store personal data for a year at the most. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you need to do with personal data in accordance with the principle of integrity and confidentiality? ","answers":[{"text":"You need to protect data with the measures that are stated in the GDPR. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need approval from the supervisory authority before you may process the data. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You need to protect data with appropriate technical and organizational measures. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "baseline-test-ii-malware":[{"question":"How does malware greatly affect people or organizations? ","answers":[{"text":"By sending threatening emails or stealing money or personal information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By stealing money or personal information, or preventing you from accessing your device. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By preventing you from accessing your device or sending threatening emails. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why do organizations increasingly suffer from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because organizations are more and more dependent on ICT. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because malware is becoming increasingly malicious. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because organizations have more trouble detecting malware. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How far does malware spread if an organization is infected with it? ","answers":[{"text":"It spreads only through the department to which the infected computer belongs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It spreads through the entire company network, but not to other organizations. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"It spreads through the entire company network or to other organizations. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is a slow computer a sign of malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because the computer can do little or nothing else if it is running malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because the computer is partially broken and therefore does not work fast anymore. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because one purpose of malware is to affect the working memory of the computer. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a sign that you are suffering from a malware infection? ","answers":[{"text":"Websites that show ads. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pop-ups that open spontaneously. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"You receive emails with an untrustworthy attachment. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you recognize malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By processes that are running while the computer is turned off. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By unknown security software that shows pop-ups. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By software that you did not install yourself. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What often happens to people who suffer from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Emails are sent in their name. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They receive emails from unknown senders. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They can no longer send attachments via email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you tell that you are suffering from malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Your antivirus program or other programs no longer work. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Your antivirus program has suddenly disappeared from your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Programs mimic each other's operations. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How come you sometimes do not notice malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Because malware is sometimes disabled. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because the signs are not always visible right away. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because you must go on the internet before malware is activated. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do to find out if you have malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Restart your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Look for unknown files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Carry out a malware scan. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Do the organization's security systems protect against malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, they are set up especially for that purpose. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Yes, but that does not guarantee anything. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, malware can easily circumvent security systems. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is your role in preventing malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Remaining alert. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Having my computer checked periodically for signs of malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Changing antivirus programs every year. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect your computer against malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By making sure you have secure hardware and software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making sure you have hardware that is not vulnerable to malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making sure you have software that protects against malware. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What should you regularly do with your programs to prevent getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Reinstall them. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Make backups. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Run updates. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"When do you have the greatest chance of getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"When you are logged in as an administrator. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When you work on the same computer a lot. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you have recently installed updates. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What risk do free antivirus programs pose? ","answers":[{"text":"They are bad at detecting malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They sometimes contain malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"There are no updates for them. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you get malware via an email from an unknown or unexpected sender? ","answers":[{"text":"By opening the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By opening the attachment. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By answering the email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which ads have the highest chance of containing malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Ads that seem too good to be true. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Ads that have images. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Ads that are only valid for a limited time. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Malware infections can be prevented by not using untrustworthy websites. What is an example of an untrustworthy website? ","answers":[{"text":"A website that you have not visited before. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A website that does not end in .net or .org. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A website offering free downloads. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What type of file should you not download if you want to prevent malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Files from people outside the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Free and/or illegal files. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Files that are larger than 2 GB. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What helps to prevent malware infections? ","answers":[{"text":"Keeping a backup of your files. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Reporting suspicious situations and incidents. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Periodically emptying your email inbox. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you help others to prevent their systems from becoming infected with malware? ","answers":[{"text":"By reporting malware to a fraud helpdesk in your country. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By forwarding suspicious emails to colleagues. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"You cannot help other people; everyone must pay attention themselves. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you remove malware from your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By searching for the malware file and moving it to the trash can on your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By deleting all downloads and updating your programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By completely erasing your hard disk and reinstalling the system and programs. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Can malware be combatted with system restoration? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"This depends on the situation. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Malicious hardware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Malicious software. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Hardware containing a virus. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can malware do? ","answers":[{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems or interrupt this access. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Allow access to your computer systems, interrupt this access, or collect sensitive information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about malware is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Malware exists in different forms, including hybrid forms. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Malware exists in different forms. There are no hybrid forms. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Malware only has one form. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Can malware end up on your computer via the internet? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, this often happens. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"No, malware can only end up on your computer via an infected USB stick. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, malware can only end up on your computer if other people infect it. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What type of software increases the chance of getting malware? ","answers":[{"text":"Software that was not installed by an ICT professional. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Software that is not up to date. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Software that is freely available on the internet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does malware end up on your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By updating free software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using free software. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By installing free software that is already infected. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How does malware end up on your computer? ","answers":[{"text":"By visiting websites that provide free music or movies and by using an unknown USB stick. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By uploading photos to the cloud or by sending emails. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By connecting your phone to the computer to charge it or by clicking on ads. ","isCorrect":false}]}],
  "baseline-test-ii-phishing":[{"question":"What is phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Looking up personal information on the internet. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Spreading malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A type of scam. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What information do phishers collect? ","answers":[{"text":"Personal data and access data. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Access data only. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Personal data only. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How do phishers gather information? ","answers":[{"text":"They search for information about you on social media. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"They pretend to be someone else to get information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"They break into the corporate network to steal data. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How does a phisher ensure that you carry out certain actions? ","answers":[{"text":"A phisher introduces himself and immediately asks you nicely to provide information. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A phisher pretends to be someone else and gets you to perform certain actions. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A phisher gives you a gift, hoping that you will perform a certain action in return. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Why is it important to prevent phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Because phishing can now also damage the hardware of your computer. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing can have a financial impact on an individual employee. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing occurs more often. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Why is phishing a threat to organizations? ","answers":[{"text":"Because phishing can cause stress to employees. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Because phishing can infect your computer with malware. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Because you no longer have access to the intranet due to phishing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is a consequence of phishing that you want to prevent? ","answers":[{"text":"That the phishing email overloads your inbox. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That phishers post sensitive information on social media. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That your organization loses information. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What consequence of phishing do you want to prevent? ","answers":[{"text":"That customers lose their confidence in your organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"That your organization has to update all its programs. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"That your organization must employ new employees to adequately protect the information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do you prevent by being alert to phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Physical threats. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Overloading the server(s). ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Reputational damage. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"At whom are basic phishing emails aimed? ","answers":[{"text":"A specific target group. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A wide audience. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Higher management. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is there a case of spear phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When a phishing email is sent to a small group of people. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a phishing email has an anonymous greeting. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When a large group of people are contacted by phone to obtain certain information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is CEO fraud? ","answers":[{"text":"Finding sensitive information about the management or the board. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Sending emails that seem to come from the management or the board. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Sending emails that seem to come from the finance department. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is spoofing? ","answers":[{"text":"Faking real websites or the emails of a reliable organization. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Sending mass emails to large organizations. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Hacking reliable organizations via their website. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is vishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When someone asks you by phone to share personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When a website asks you to click on a link. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When someone asks you to share personal information via social media. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What is smishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When you receive an SMS with a strange photo. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you click on a fake URL on your phone. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When you receive an SMS with a fake URL. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"What kind of phishing mail is an example of whaling? ","answers":[{"text":"A personalized phishing mail that was sent to an employee of the financial department. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A phishing mail that was sent to a large group of board members or directors. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A personalized phishing mail that was sent to a member of the board or director. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How can you recognize a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"By an anonymous greeting. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By language use without spelling mistakes. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By a logo of a well-known organization. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What can be a characteristic of a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"The mail contains an attachment. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"The mail contains bad spelling and grammar. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"The mail does not have a logo in it. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is an email with a link phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"When the link is written out in full. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When the link occurs several times in the email. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When the URL does not match the link in the text. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You recognize phishing by a misleading domain name. Where in the URL is the domain name? ","answers":[{"text":"After the www. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"After the extension (for example .com). ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Before the first single slash. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Which of the following statements about the use of HTTP and HTTPS is true? ","answers":[{"text":"Phishing links use HTTP more often than HTTPS. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Phishing links use HTTPS more often than HTTP. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"HTTPS means that the link is not phishing. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of pop-ups are a sign of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Pop-ups with images. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Pop-ups that ask for login details. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Pop-ups about cookies. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What information do phishers ask for? ","answers":[{"text":"Personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Your position within the company. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Public information. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What do phishers often ask for in a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"Address details. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Money. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Your mobile phone number. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"Which of these threats could you typically encounter in a phishing email? ","answers":[{"text":"'If you do not change your login details within 24 hours, you will no longer have access.' ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"'Your current password is 2 months old; change it within 7 days.' ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"'If you do not pay the invoice within 30 days, additional administration costs will be charged.' ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"When is a message that appears to be from the government a phishing attack? ","answers":[{"text":"When it tells you that there is information ready for you online. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"When it asks for personal information. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"When it tells you that your passport has expired and you have to apply for a new one. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What kind of message suggests that it is a phishing attack? ","answers":[{"text":"A message about a document that has expired. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"An advertising message from a company that you haven't bought anything from for a long time. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A message with an invoice for a product that you've never bought. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"Through which of the following characteristics can you recognize phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"A message about a lottery with which you can win a world tour. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"A message with an offer for a trial subscription. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"A message that there will be maintenance on the intranet. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"What should you do with an email when you think it is phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"Delete the email immediately so that I do not get malware. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Forward the email to the responsible person or department, so that the sender can be blocked. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"Send an email to my colleagues to warn them about the phishing email so that they do not click on the link. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect yourself from phishing over the internet? ","answers":[{"text":"By making bookmarks for frequently used websites. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By only visiting known websites. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By checking the safety label on the website. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"You receive an email from a webshop you have not placed an order with. The webshop asks you to enter your customer details again. What should you do? ","answers":[{"text":"Check whether the email contains signs of phishing and click on the link if the email appears to be safe. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Click the link. I've received emails from this webshop before, so I know that the link is safe. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"Go to my webshop account and check that my details are correct. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"How can you protect your data against the effects of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"By storing my data in the cloud. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By making backups. ","isCorrect":true},{"text":"By not sending my data via email. ","isCorrect":false}]},{"question":"How can you protect yourself against the consequences of phishing? ","answers":[{"text":"By only using software that comes from the organization. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By only using free software that is familiar to me. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"By using security software. ","isCorrect":true}]},{"question":"You are logged in as an administrator and use the internet. Is this safe? ","answers":[{"text":"Yes, because the firewall protects against the effects of phishing. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because phishers mainly focus on people with administrator rights. ","isCorrect":false},{"text":"No, because you are more vulnerable to the consequences of phishing. ","isCorrect":true}]}],
  "cyberfsfvvdecsufvrity":[],
  "cybervfsfvdecsufrity":[],
  "cyberfsfvvdecsufrity":[],
  "cybersfcdecsuffrity":[]
}